Janah Abu Hassan

Atlanta, GA 30308 | (470) 685-5698 | janahabuhassan@gatech.edu

Objective

Junior at Georgia Institute of Technology, pursuing a bachelor's degree in computer engineering, with over 2 years of experience developing user-focused systems. Working knowledge of web development, Python, and Java with a passion for Artificial Intelligence, deep learning (DL) and statistical machine learning (ML). Seeking a summer internship starting summer of 2023, where experience can be applied to work on some of the most ambitious technical problems, develop new solutions that will impact the future of the company, and work in a collaborative environment.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology | Atlanta, GA

August 2020 - Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, GPA 3.50

Expected Graduation, December 2024

Oxbridge Tutorial College | Lagos, Nigeria

A-Level Degree, GPA 4.0

September 2018 – June 2020

Work Experience and Clubs

Campus Recreation Center (CRC) | Georgia Tech

August 2021 – December 2021

Member Services Student Assistant

- Supplied building access to members, visitors, and employees.
- Oversaw various gym equipment and keys.
- Provided quality customer service to hundreds of patrons bilingually, in Arabic and English, to build brand loyalty.
- Identified patron needs through active listening techniques to refer them to colleagues or higher desks.
- Handled calls, with duties including referring, advising, and guiding members, visitors, and contractors.
- Trained 2 new employees as they shadowed me while on duty.

RoboJackets | Georgia Tech

August 2020 - May 2021

RoboNav software team

- Developed skills in C++ and ROS.
- Learned the fundamentals of automated robots, including the software, electrical, mechanical, and hardware aspects.

Student Representative Council | Oxbridge Tutorial College

September 2019 – May 2020

Treasurer

- Managed the budgeting and kept a ledger of the money spent for school events, overseeing about \$1,500.
- Helped save up about \$500 from the profits from school events to fund the building of a canopy above the pavilion in the school's basketball court.

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Django, Git

Hardware: Raspberry Pi, Arduino

Communication: Design proposals, technical reports, presentations (large and small audiences)

Languages: Arabic (fluent), English (fluent)

Projects

Interactive Resume Website

Summer 2022

Individual Project / www.janahabuhassan.com

Created, and constantly maintaining an interactive resume website using HTML, CSS, and jQuery, which shows all
achievements, skills, awards, and more. Completed the project in about 1.5 weeks.

Python Chatbot Fall 2020

Individual Project / ECE Discovery Studio / https://github.com/janah-2/chatbot

• Created a chatbot using Python, specified to prepare users for job interviews by answering job interview questions and helping practice for the job interview. Used statistical machine learning (ML) libraries such as TensorFlow and tflearn, which also helped me gain experience in the use of neural networking and Natural Language Processing (NLP). Completed this project in 2 weeks instead of the allotted 4.

Django To-do List Summer 2020

Individual Project / https://github.com/janah-2/django-todolist / http://janah.pythonanywhere.com

• Created a to-do list using Django, a Python framework. This website allows users to login, logout, register, create lists, create items within the list, features different pages, and more. Completed this project in about 1 week.